Welcome to the demonstration
video for the chemotherapy
hazardous drug CSP manipulation.
Please review the step by step
procedure in the procedural lab
portion of the textbook.
The compounder has performed
hand hygiene and garbing for the
hazardous drug clean room.
All the supplies used in this
hazardous drug CSP have been
wiped off with 70% IPA using a
sterile lint free wiper before
introducing items into the
biological safety cabinet.
The compounder is wiping the
chemo gloves off with a pre
saturated 70% IPA wiper and then
placing that wiper into the
yellow sharps container.
Open the outer packaging of the
IV bag and you'll discard that
packaging in the yellow Chemo
Sharps container.
Next, we'll open the packaging
of the tubing and you'll discard
that outer wrapper and you'll
position the tubing in your hand
so that you will have access to
this roll clamp.
And then we're going to roll
that clamp closed and we're
going to place this tubing so
that we it's not going to
interfere with us going into the
bag.
You're going to remove the pull
tag that covers the Ivy bag
tubing port and I like to tuck
the injection port so that you
have easy access to that tubing
port.
And then we're going to
carefully make sure that we get
all the way into a nice seal
inside of that bag port.
You're going to pinch the drip
chamber once or twice.
This tubing has a vented cap.
So we are going to open the roll
clamp on that tubing very slowly
and we're going to watch that
fluid fill the four tubing.
When it gets to the end of that
vented cap, we'll roll that
clamp closed and then we'll
momentarily set that back on the
work surface.
We're going to open a red tip
cap and once you peel back the
packaging, you want to be
careful to ensure that you don't
touch contaminate the critical
site of this red tip, using your
knuckle to help you because the
gloves are slick.
And then we'll place that on the
work surface.
We're going to bring our chemo
vial onto the chemo mat and
we'll open a sterile IPA swab
for the cap of the chemo
dispensing pan.
Be aware of the vertical airflow
from the HEPA filter that is
going to come over the sterile
IPA pad and then place that on
the work surface.
We're going to open the cap of
our chemo vial and put it in our
chemo Sharps container.
And then we're open another
sterile IPA swab and we'll clean
the stopper of our vial and you
can kind of clean up as you go.
We'll open our chemo dispensing
pin.
It's a closed system.
There's caps on both of those
ends and then we'll discard that
outer packaging.
And we want to hold on to that
chemo dispensing pin with our
forefinger and our thumb and
then we're going to put that
into the vial in a twisting
motion.
We'll hold on to the outer flap
and we'll take that cap off of
that chemo dispensing pin.
Let's go ahead and push that
flat knob so that we can
activate our syringe before we
bring it out of the packaging
and then we'll discarded that
packaging into the Sharps
container.
We want to hold on to our vial,
hold on to the flaps and then
we're going to turn so that we
can see those graduation marks.
I like to pull chemo at the 10
o'clock 4:00 position.
When you get some fluid, we will
remove that air pocket that came
from that chemo dispensing pin
at 12:00 and 6:00 and then we'll
get right back into that 10 and
four position and we'll pull out
the volume of the chemo for our
patient dose.
Notice that the airflow is going
vertically over our critical
sites as we pull that plunger
out.
We now have a critical site of
that inner plunger.
Once we get to the volume that
we need by the barrel, we will
go to 8:00 and 2:00.
We'll hold on to the flaps of
our chemo vial and then we will
come off carefully off that
chemo dispensing pin go nice and
slow.
Sometimes there will be a bead
of chemo and then we'll set that
vial back on the work service.
We're going to open our syringe,
the outer packaging and
carefully put that on to our
syringe.
And then we're going to pick up
that vial and we're going to
place that cap back on our vial.
We'll get the check from the
pharmacist and then that vial
can go into our chemo Sharps
container.
We're going to bring our bag in
preparation to inject our chemo.
We'll get a sterile IPA swab and
put that on the work surface,
and then we'll get a second
sterile IPA swab.
Notice the airflow from the HEPA
filter and we'll clean off the
injection port of the bag.
And then we're going to get into
a dark position and we're going
to go in at 8:00 and 2:00.
We're going to position our
fingers on the flaps of the
syringe to help us.
And with the thumb, we're going
to push on that flat knob and
we're going to inject the chemo
into our bag.
Notice that I don't need to put
the needle all the way into the
bag.
We don't want to poke any of the
outer part of that bag.
We're going to come out by the
barrel slightly and then with
the thumb we're going to pull
back on that plunger to get what
is in the hub and the lumen so
that we don't have a bead of
chemo on this tubing port.
Once you come out, you can
discard that syringe in your
Sharps container.
We're going to open a sterile
IPA pad and we're going to clean
off the port of our and then
we're going to get a pre
saturated sterile 70% IPA wiper.
We make sure that we have an
opening to our empty bag so that
once we wipe off our bag and our
tubing, we can get into that
empty plastic bag.
We'll wipe off the entire bag
and the tubing and then we'll
discard that wiper in our chemo
sharps container.
And then we'll place the chemo
bag inside our our plastic bag
and we'll close it and then
we'll get another pre saturated
70% IPA wiper and we'll wipe off
that outer bag and we'll hand it
to our pharmacist.
The compounder has just finished
making the chemotherapy CSP and
now disposing of the chemo mat.
Fold it up and put it in the
chemo sharps container and then
we'll clean off the DCA work
surface with a pre saturated 70%
IPA wiper.
And then we'll dispose of that
wiper in the sharps container.
And then we'll take off these
outer gloves and dispose of them
inside of the hood in this
sharps container.